navionics.com 2015-12-05

# Privacy Policy | Navionics

If you are looking for privacy policy concerning our mobile applications, please click here

We are committed to protecting your privacy and keeping you informed on how your information is collected, protected and used.

Please read our Privacy Policy to understand how we use and protect the information you provide to us or obtained from those visiting this website (the “Website”). By using the Website, you accept the collection, retention and use of your personal information in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

We collect data to provide you services such as the registration to the website, the access to the web store, the support for the use of our products, as well as to keep you updated regarding our products and our initiatives, to improve our products and services and to offer you a better experience when you contact us for any reason.

Data are collected in two forms:

**DATA PROVIDED BY YOU**

To subscribe to our newsletter, to contact us or to access to our web store, we ask for some personal information such as name, email address, phone or credit card number. Some of this information is required to provide you with the service you have requested, and the failure to provide such information may make it impossible to access that service. Your personal data may also be used, with your consent, to send you promotional and information about our products and services, to carry out market research or direct sales via e -mail, MMS, SMS. Permission for use of this data for such purposes is optional and any refusal will not affect in any way your Site registration or the access to our web store. You'll be able to object at any time the processing of your data, even partially, by sending an email to [privacy@navionics.it](mailto:privacy@navionics.it), and indicating if you want to object to the entire processing, or for example, only to the sending of promotional communications.

**DATA COLLECTED FROM US**

These data are implicitly transmitted by the use of Internet communication protocols that we collect as you browse the site. This information is not collected to be associated with identified parties, but by their very nature may, through processing and association with data held by third parties, allow users to be identified. This category of data includes IP addresses or domain names of computers used by users connecting to the site, the URI (Uniform Resource Identifier) of requested resources, the time of request, the method used to submit the request to the server, the size of the file obtained in reply, the numerical code indicating the status of the reply provided by the server (successful, error, etc.) and other parameters regarding the operating system and computer environment of the user. These data are used only to obtain anonymous statistical information on site use and to check its correct functioning and are deleted immediately after processing. The data may be used to ascertain responsibility in case of hypothetical computer crimes against the site: apart for this possibility, at present data on web contacts do not remain for more than seven days.

**COOKIES**

**What are cookies**

Cookies are small text files that the websites visited by users send to their terminals, where they are stored to be re-transmitted to the same websites during subsequent visits.

**Cookies used by the Website and their purpose**

The Website uses technical cookies, which are intended to ensure the proper functioning of some sections, such as access to the private area of the website, to provide certain customization features and to improve your browsing experience.

The first time you visit the Website, you will be asked to accept cookies through a banner. You can refuse to accept all, or certain, cookies or can change, even after, the settings of your computer so you know when you receive cookies or you can disable the automatic acceptance of cookies. Closing the banner, scrolling the page of the Website, clicking on any page of the website, you agree to the use of cookies.

The Website uses the following types of technical cookies:

· Browsing cookies, which enable the Website to function correctly, for example, allowing you to browse between pages and access to the private area;

· Functional Cookies, which allow you to activate specific features of the Website and to store your preferences (such as language),in order to improve your browsing experience;

· Analytical Cookies, which allow to capture statistical information in aggregate and anonymous form, in relation to the browsing preference.

In order to analyze how the website is being used, it is used Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. ("Google") that utilizes cookies stored on your computer to allow us statistical analysis. The data collected are aggregated and do not allow in any way to identify you. To consult the privacy policy of Google on the Google Analytics service visit the website <http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html>. To learn about the privacy policies of Google, please visit the website  <http://www.google.com/intl/it/privacy/privacy-policy.html>. The Cookies of Google Analytics can be refused according to the procedure described by Google (<https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=it>). Therefore, by continuing to browse this website without disabling cookies by Google Analytics, you agree to the use of your data by Google, limited to the methods and purposes stated above.

The site does not use profiling cookies.

**How to disable cookies**

You can refuse consent to the use of cookies by selecting specific settings of your browser. Please be aware that disabling cookies may affect your ability to use all the features of the Website.

Below you will find links that explain how to disable cookies for the most popular browsers (for other browsers, please check the Help section of the software which is usually accessible from the F1 key):

**I** **nternet Explorer** : Choose the menu “tools” then “Internet Options”. Click on the “privacy” tab. Move the slider to the top to block all cookies.

**Google Chrome** : Click the wrench icon on the browser toolbar. Select Settings. Click on “Show advanced settings”. In the “Privacy” section, click the “Content settings” button. Select “Block sites from setting any data”.

**Mozilla Firefox** : Choose the menu “tools” then “Options”. Click on the icon “Privacy”. Under Settings history: select “Use custom settings”. To enable cookies, check “Accept cookies for sites”; to disable uncheck “Accept cookies for sites”.

**Safari** : Choose the menu Safari then "Preferences". Click on "Privacy" then “Details” to select the website and click "Remove".

The data collected are processed using electronic means for the time strictly needed to achieve the purposes for which such data are collected, except for their transformation into anonymous form that does not allow in any way, nor indirectly through combination with other data, to trace your identity. The data collected with your consent for marketing purposes will be stored for a period not exceeding twenty-four months from their registration.

To prevent the loss of data, their accidental destruction, damaging, unlawful or improper and unauthorized access, specific safety measure are observed, such as TLS / SSL and other protocols in compliance with applicable regulations.

The data are processed and stored in our offices in Via Fondacci, 269, Industrial Area Montramito - 55054 Massarosa (Lu), Italy.

The databases and servers in which your personal information may be stored are guarded by Amazon Web Services, Inc. in the US and are managed exclusively by the technical staff responsible for processing or by persons appointed to conduct periodic maintenance. Amazon has adhered to the US-EU Safe Harbor as determined by the US Department of Commerce for the collection, use and storage of data of the European Union and will handle personal data received from the European Union in accordance with the principles of the said “Safe Harbor”. For further information about the Safe Harbor program and to view the certification of Amazon, please visit : <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

Your personal information will not be disclosed to the public and may be provided only for the purposes specified above to the following categories of persons: (i) our employees, (ii) individuals, companies, associations or professionals who have been appointed to carry out on our behalf assistance services and activites and advice related to commercial activity.

The Data Controller is Navionics S.p.A.with registered office in Milan, Corso Magenta, 43 – 20123 – Italy and offices in Via Fondacci, 269, Industrial area Montramito - 55054 Massarosa Italy.

Navionics SpA appointed the Data Processors, whose updated list can be requested by sending an email to the following address [privacy@navionics.it](mailto:privacy@navionics.it).

You can access your data at any time and ask for an update, correction or integration if they are inaccurate or incomplete, the cancellation, anonymization or blocking of unlawfully processed data. You shall object, in whole or in part, for legitimate reasons, their treatment and/or their use as far as the sending of commercial communications and you can exercise the other rights under Art. 7 of the Italian Legislative Decree 196/2003, by contacting Navionics Spa, by mail to the following address: Via Fondacci , 269, Z.I. Montramito - 55054 Massarosa Italy, or by e - mail at the following address: [privacy@navionics.it](mailto:privacy@navionics.it).

Our Privacy Policy may be changed from time to time to reflect changes in legislation, technology, changes in the collection and use of data, commercial initiatives. In case of changes, we will notify you: (i) by notice published on the main page of the Site and/or (ii) taking any other action we may deem appropriate. Any changes will be effective as of the time of publication, and the browsing of the Site after such time will be deemed as acceptance of such changes.

Updated August 25, 2015
